bettingexpert.com 2019-07-21

# Privacy Policy bettingexpert - Read our Privacy Policy

**What information can be found in this Policy?**

1\. Introduction

2\. Data Controller and Data Subjects

3 Types of Data and Reasons for Processing  
3.1 Identification data  
3.2 Special financial data  
3.3 Recordings  
3.4 Private habits and interests

4\. Our use of cookies

5\. How we protect your data

6\. Your rights  
7.1 Right to Information  
6.2 Right of access  
6.3 Right to rectification  
6.4 Right to erasure (Right to be forgotten)  
6.5 Right to restrict processing  
6.6 Right to object to the processing of your data  
6.7 Right Not to Be the Subject of Automated Decision Making  
6.8 Right to data portability  
6.9 Right to withdraw consent  
6.9.1 How to Opt-out  
6.10 Right to lodge a complaint  
6.11 How to Exercise Your Rights

7\. Data Retention

8\. Who your personal data can be shared with

19\. Transfer of your data to third countries

10\. Endnotes

## 1\. Introduction

A bettingexpert user (‘you’) may share information and opinions on sport matches, search for tips, compete to be the most successful tipster on sport matches, check the match statistics, get reviews of bookmakers and information about free bets (‘services’). More information about our services is available in our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.bettingexpert.com/about#what-is-bettingexpert).

This Privacy Policy is important for you to understand how your personal data is collected, used, consulted or otherwise processed when you use [www.bettingexpert.com](http://www.bettingexpert.com/) (‘bettingexpert’). This Privacy Policy applies to your personal data processing on bettingexpert, and not to data processing that may occur on other websites. The owner of bettingexpert (‘we’, ‘us’, ‘our’) is:

Better Collective A/S,  
Tolbodgade 12,  
1253 Copenhagen K (Hovedstaden)  
Denmark (DK)  
CVR. 27652913

## 2\. Data Controller and Data Subjects

By using bettingexpert services you may disclose various pieces of information, including those that are considered as personal data. When your personal data is processed, you are considered to be data subject and you are entitled to exercise your rights guaranteed by EU Data Protection Law and as explained in this Privacy Policy. Taking into account that we determine the purposes and means of processing personal data on bettingexpert we are legally considered to be data controller over your personal data on this website. Being a data controller provides us with the opportunity to process your personal data, but also obligates us to protect it in the way regulated by the EU Data Protection Law, particularly the General Data Protection Regulation (‘GDPR’) and this Privacy Policy.

## 3\. Types of Data and Reasons for Processing

We may process various categories of your personal data in order to provide our services to you, improve your experience with our services, further develop our services and to secure and maintain regular functionality of bettingexpert. More information about the types of data that we process, as well as the purposes for processing these types of data can be found below.

### 3.1 Identification data

Personal Identifiable Information (PII) - When you create your account on bettingexpert we process your email address, username, display name and the ID that is assigned by our system. We may also process your first name, last name, address, phone and mobile phone number if you choose to add them to your profile. Finally, in certain circumstances, you may be asked to send to us a copy of your government issued ID (e.g. passport) so that we can verify your identity.

Your PII is processed so that we are able to distinguish you from other registered users on bettingexpert. Your email address is used so that we can communicate with you regarding any changes to your account or our services, as well as to send you newsletters and push notifications upon your consent.

It is your choice whether you decide to reveal your real forename, surname, address, phone and mobile phone number. This information may contribute to the personalisation of your user account and development of your communication channels with us. If you win one of our competitions and are entitled to a prize, you will be asked to send your forename, surname, phone number and a copy of your ID so that we are able to verify your identity and transfer the prize to you

Electronic identification data - When you log in to bettingexpert we process the IP address of the device you use, the type and version of browser and operating system you use, as well as the time of logging in. If you are logging in via social networks, they will generate ‘social tokens’ that act as your authentication data that we process whenever you want to login to bettingexpert via social networks.

We process the IP address of the device you use in order to enable communication between your device and our server and to determine your approximate geolocation, which may be further used for service customisation (for example, to provide appropriate content for your language of choice and gambling-related content that is legal in your country). Your approximate location may also be used for analytical purposes. More information about how we process your data for analytical purposes can be found in our Cookie Policy. The processing of details about the browser and operating system you use is necessary to ensure the regular provision of our services to you. We may also need this data to solve technical problems should they emerge.

If you log in via social networks, we do not use any information available on your social network accounts and profiles. If you decide to login via your social network account, social network tokens will be generated and then used solely for authentication purposes.

### 3.2 Special financial data

Financial identification data - We will process details about your Skrill/Paypal account if you win a cash prize on our websiteadd them to your account. We need this data in order to transfer the prize to you.

### 3.3 Recordings

Images - You can choose to upload a profile picture on to your account. It can be a photo of you, or any other picture that you wish to be linked to your account. We may store your profile picture to allow personalisation of your profile on our website.

### 3.4 Private habits and interests

Tips - Some of your interactions with our website require public use of information, namely when you post a tip. When you post a tip we have to process information about your tip such as the date and time of the tip, the event that the tip relates to, tip language and your comments that clarify the tip.

We also create statistics about the success of your tipping activities and process information necessary to carry out competition among tipsters (e.g. to confirm which tipster has the highest level of successful predictions).

Information that we process about tips that you post is necessary for the creation of tips and making them available for users and visitors of bettingexpert. The statistics that we create about the success of tipping activities are necessary to carry out transparent and fair competitions among tipsters.

Preferences - We process information about tipsters you follow on bettingexpert, as well as information about your interests, such as your preferred content on bettingexpert and the services you use.

We may also process information that you complete in the ‘About Me’ section of your profile, which includes a description of yourself, as well as your interests and information about your social network accounts.

Information about your followers and tipsters that you follow is available to all bettingexpert users and visitors. We strongly support the value of transparency and for that reason we consider that each tipster, potential tipster or just a visitor should have the opportunity to gauge the success and reliability of each tipster. Tipsters can also share their knowledge with other people.

We process information about your interests in order to recognise your personal preferences that may be used for commercial communication purposes. For this purpose we may use marketing platforms that are explained in more detail in our Cookie Policy. If you do not want oto be subject to automated decision making, including profiling, please check the subsections ‘Right to Object to the Processing of Your Data’ and ‘Right Not to Be the Subject of Automated Decision Making’ under the section ‘Your Rights’ in this policy for more information.

## 4\. Our use of cookies

Any browser visiting our website will receive cookies from us. We use cookies because we wish to provide the best possible on-site experience to everyone who visits our website. Through the use of cookies we process standard internet log information and details of the behavioural pattern of our website visitors. The use of cookies enables us to improve site navigation, analyse on-site behaviour of everyone who visits the website, promote our products and provide content from third parties. To find out more about our use of cookies, and how you can disable them please read our Cookie Policy.

## 5\. How we protect your data

We do not collect or retain your personal data longer than is necessary for the purposes explained above.

We use technical and organisational measures in accordance with good industry practice to ensure appropriate security of your personal data against accidental or unlawful loss, alteration, theft, unauthorised disclosure or access, unauthorised use and against all other unlawful forms of processing.

## 6\. Your rights

You have the right to be provided with certain pieces of information about the processing of your data and your relation with us. This includes our identity and contact details, the reasons or purposes for processing your personal data, the legal basis for doing so, recipients of that data (especially if they reside in third countries) and other relevant information that is necessary to ensure the fair and transparent processing of your personal data.

### 6.1 Right of access

You have the right to obtain confirmation from us as to whether or not personal data concerning you is being processed information about the processing of your data and your rights and where applicable to request access to the data.

### 6.2 Right to rectification

You have the right to ask us to delete inaccurate personal data concerning you. Taking into account the purposes of the data processing, you have the right to have incomplete personal data completed and inaccurate data to be corrected.

### 6.3 Right to erasure (Right to be forgotten)

In limited circumstances you have the right to request that we erase the information we hold about you. These are as follows:

  * Where the data is no longer needed for the purposes it was collected

  * Where you have withdrawn consent for the processing of your data and there is no other lawful basis on which we can continue to process your data

  * Where you objected to the processing and there are no overriding legitimate grounds to continue

  * Where the data has been unlawfully processed

  * Where the data has to be erased for the purpose of the compliance with a legal obligation.

We will be exempt from this obligation if it is impossible to comply with or would require disproportionate effort to prove.

### 6.4 Right to restrict processing

You have the right to seek the restriction of the processing of your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * If the accuracy of the data is contested,processing may be restricted for the period necessary to allow us to verify its’ accuracy

  * The processing is unlawful and you request restriction instead of erasure

  * We no longer need the data for the purposes it was collected, but data is still needed in connection with establishing, exercising and defending legal rights.

  * If you objected to the processing of your personal data while awaiting verification on whether our legitimate interests for processing your data overrides the interest of your fundamental rights and freedoms.

### 6.5 Right to object to the processing of your data

At any time you have the right to object to our processing of your data (including profiling) on grounds relating to your particular situation. Upon your objection, we will stop processing your data unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for continuing the processing which override interests of your fundamental freedoms and rights, or if further processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

### 6.6 Right Not to Be the Subject of Automated Decision Making

You have the right to object to our processing of your data for automated decision making, including profiling, where such processing produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you. Upon your legitimate objection, your personal data will no longer be processed for automated decision making. You also have the right to request human intervention in relation to automated decision making about you.

### 6.7 Right to data portability

Under certain circumstances you have right to receive your personal data which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format (i.e. in digital form). You have the right to request the transmission of those data to another entity without hindrance from us, if such transmission is technically feasible.

### 6.8 Right to withdraw consent

We rely on your consent to send you emails with newsletters and push notifications that contain the hottest tips and latest offers from bookmakers that we are partnered with. You can withdraw your consent at any time without giving any reason to us and without any charge to you.

The withdrawal of consent does not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its’ withdrawal. After the consent is withdrawn we will not be able to share the latest tips, news and offers with you.

### 6.9 How to Opt-out

To opt-out from receiving newsletter emails from us, you should:

  * Click on the unsubscribe link available at the bottom of any email that you have received or

  * Unsubscribe from the preference center page

You can turn off push notifications through your browser settings. Please visit [this website](https://documentation.onesignal.com/v5.0/docs/opt-out-of-web-push) for detailed instructions on how to opt-out of Web Push.

### 6.10 Right to lodge a complaint

If you feel that your personal data rights have been breached, you have the right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority. The relevant data protection authority in EU Member States may be determined either by your place of habitual residence, or the place where the alleged infringement emerged.

As we are established in Denmark you may choose to contact the [Danish Data Protection Agency](https://www.datatilsynet.dk/kontakt/).

### 6.11 How to Exercise Your Rights

If you have any questions regarding the processing of your personal data explained in this Privacy Policy, or wish to exercise any of your rights as listed above in the ‘Your Rights’ section, please send us an email at dataprotection@bettercollective.com.

## 7\. Data Retention

We will store your data in the database even if you delete your account. In this case your profile data will not be publicly displayed. Tips that you have previously posted will stay publicly accessible due to the fact that we hold intellectual property rights over them. However, the remaining tips will be depersonalised which means that it is impossible to link any of these tips with your personal data.

If you would like your personal data to be deleted from our systems, you can send an erasure request by using the process described in the section above.

## 8\. Who your personal data can be shared with

We may share your data with third parties. The third parties are categorised as follows:

  * Members of the Better Collective Group (the BC Group) which includes Better Collective A/S and its’ subsidiaries. Please be aware that we determine the purpose and means of the processing of your data, as well as deciding which of your data is going to be processed by other members of the BC Group. More information about the members of the BC Group is available [here](https://bettercollective.com/contact/).

  * Entities who help us to regularly provide and further develop our services (e.g. analytics, maintenance, marketing and development). They are allowed to process your information as reasonably necessary in order to perform delegated tasks. Please be aware that only we determine the purpose and means of the processing of your data, as well as deciding which of your data is going to be processed to perform delegated tasks.

  * Public authorities and law enforcement agencies when we are legally required or permitted to do so.

## 9\. Transfer of your data to third countries

We may transfer your personal data outside of the European Economic Area in order to provide our services on regular basis and/or to develop our services further. We take all measures in relation to the recipients of your personal data to ensure an adequate level of protection and appropriate safeguards, as defined by the applicable data protection law and particularly GDPR, are implemented.

Your personal data may be transferred to a recipient based in a country that the European Commission considers to have an adequate level of data protection. You may find out more about countries with an adequate level of protection [here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en).

If your data is transferred to a recipient based in the US, we aim to transfer your data in the way set out by the Privacy Shield mechanism. More information about the Privacy Shield mechanism is available [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/Program-Overview).

We will conclude Data Protection Agreements with recipients of your data where necessary. These will include Standard Contractual Clauses issued by the European Commission that would obligate the data recipient to provide an adequate level of protection and implement appropriate safeguards as defined by the applicable data protection law, and particularly GDPR, with regard to the processing your personal data.

## 10\. Endnotes

This Privacy Policy may be modified from time to time.

Essential modifications are those that affect your rights, obligations and state with regards to the protection and processing of your personal data. The essential modifications may include, but are not limited to, launch of new services, deployment of new technologies and processing your data for new purposes. If we make essential modifications to this Privacy Policy, we will send you notice through our Services, or by other means and give you the opportunity to review the changes before they become effective.

Minor modifications are those that do not impact your rights, obligations and state with regards to the protection of your personal data. These types of modifications may include, but are not limited to, structure, organisational and grammatical changes to this Privacy Policy in order to make our policy easier to read.
